<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-04-13T15:18:59+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Travels with Mally</title><subtitle>Tales of an American who moved to the south of France during the coronavirus pandemic.</subtitle><author><name>Mallory Shaner</name></author><entry><title type="html">On A Final Day Trip</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/On-A-Final-Day-Trip/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On A Final Day Trip" /><published>2021-04-13T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-04-13T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/On-A-Final-Day-Trip</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/On-A-Final-Day-Trip/">&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Yellow church.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Yellow church.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Everything here is yellow instead of alabaster white like Avignon.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last weekend was our last week of freedom (to an extent) before lockdown number 3 began. The government announced confinement on Wednesday, but it wasn’t set to begin until Saturday at midnight. With this knowledge in hand, a few of us piled into a car and drove to Aix-en-Provence for the day on Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img right-inline&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Flower market one.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Flower market one.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Gorgeous flower market in front of city hall.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img left-inline&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Flower market two.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Flower market two.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Non-existent March showers bring April flowers in Provence I guess.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite starting the day with a few hiccups, the drive got off to a lovely start. The weather was approaching the 70s and it was sunny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Lourmarin Streets.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Lourmarin Streets.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;We got really lucky with the weather.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we got to Aix, we realized pretty much everyone else had the same idea as us. The city was flooded with people, and there was also a market going on along the main drag. With a group of six of us, it was kind of hard to stick together. We spent the morning splitting up and finding each other again at various points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/All smiles.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/All smiles.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;So happy to be reunited.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was my second time in Aix, but the first time was in October on a Sunday for about two hours. That time it was empty and dead, and this time it was the exact opposite. So I feel like I can’t really form an opinion about a city I’ve only seen two extremes of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Jack takes France.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Jack takes France.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Seeing Jack in France, here, with me, is kind of wild. Even though he's been here for 12 days, I still have to pinch myself sometimes.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless, I like its colorful palette, the winding largely, pedestrian-only streets in the centre ville, and good mix of boutiques and chains. We split up for lunch but then met again to eat at a fountain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Fountain Friends.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Fountain Friends.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Enjoying a meal sitting by a fountain. Natassja, Margaret, Briar, Rama, from left to right.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some poké, we broke off to continue exploring. Jack and I mainly walked around and didn’t head into any stores. The city felt just enormously crowded and it was kind of overwhelming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img right-inline&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Masked smiles.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Masked smiles.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;You cannot tell at all but we are smiling under here.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img left-inline&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Crowds.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Crowds.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;This does not even do the crowds justice.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We did stop into a wine store that was located in a basement off of the Cours Mirabeau, where the vendor was kind enough to let us sample some gin. I’ve never sampled gin straight before. Do not recommend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Cave.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Cave.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Aforementioned wine shop where we got some Coteaux-d'Aix Rosé.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Aix-en-Provence, we decided to take a scenic route and stop in Lourmarin on our way back to Avignon. The drive was stunning - I chose a toll-free route on Google Maps not knowing it would be as stunning as it was. We drove out of Aix through these winding roads in the northern area and it was gorgeous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img right-inline&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Cicadas.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Cicadas.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Cicadas are considered good luck charms in Provence.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img left-inline&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Dried fleurs.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Dried fleurs.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Does anything scream Provence more ?&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lourmarin is one of the famous Luberon villages, but unlike Gordes it is not on a hillside. However, it does have a gorgeous castle next to the downtown area and a field that had some donkeys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img right-inline&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Castle one.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Castle one.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;We couldn't go inside the castle, but the views were gorgeous.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img left-inline&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Castle two.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Castle two.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Imagine this being your country home.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We explored the quaint village, stopped into some boutiques, and sat by the castle. It was really peaceful and a nice way to end the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img right-inline&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Glamour shot.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Glamour shot.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;It seems like due to COVID, I have so many more solo shots than I ever did abroad.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img left-inline&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Bench.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Bench.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A man and his bench. That is probably incredibly old.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, our day trip had to come to an end on the earlier side so we could return the car in time for curfew. But it was a nice way to spend the last bits of freedom and we really enjoyed exploring some new areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img right-inline&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Donkey.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Donkey.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Gotta love seeing random donkeys in the south of France.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img left-inline&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Castle three.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Castle three.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;There was a wine store under the castle, which was filled with cool local finds.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, this four week confinement works and we can explore a little bit more on the other side. If not, at least France isn’t going anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Lourmarin village.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-04-13/Lourmarin village.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A classic Luberon village view never gets old.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name>Mallory Shaner</name></author><category term="immersion" /><category term="France" /><category term="pandemic" /><category term="language" /><category term="travel" /><category term="French" /><category term="expat" /><category term="America" /><category term="Luberon" /><category term="Lourmarin" /><category term="Aix-en-Provence" /><category term="Provence" /><category term="Aix" /><summary type="html">Everything here is yellow instead of alabaster white like Avignon.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On Some Updates</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/On-Some-Updates/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Some Updates" /><published>2021-04-12T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-04-12T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/On-Some-Updates</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/On-Some-Updates/">&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-24/Sunset Uno.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-24/Sunset Uno.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Can't not post these photos of the sunset and the street.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know it’s been more than a hot minute since I have blogged, but things have been kind of busy/ever-changing here. Since I last blogged, I talked about being frustrated with differing COVID responses and just all-around fatigued with this new normal, especially as things diverge between France responses and American.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ironically enough, just two days after I posted that, France announced a new lockdown with the addition of schools closing. This sent everyone into somewhat of a frenzy. The government said schools would do one week of remote learning, then a nationwide two-week spring break (normally the breaks are staged across three zones of France), with the plan to have elementary school students resume in-person learning the last week of April and middle/high school the first week of May. This meant for me 3 weeks of vacation and for my friends who taught high school and middle school, the end of the program (because our contracts end April 30).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite it being the eve of my birthday, it didn’t feel very celebratory. While this confinement was more lax than the one we went through in November and the one last year, it still meant some significant changes to our life that we had finally adjusted to. We also knew this likely meant the last week for many people who hadn’t been home since October, and with schools closed no real reason to stay. The new rules for confinement mean all non-essential businesses are closed, with the exception of take-out for restaurants, hair salons, grocery stores (and any stores selling food/drink so wine stores, bakeries, and cheese shops are all still open - thank God), and a few select businesses such as bookstores and video game stores. Additionally, you can’t go further than 10 KM from your residence without a compelling reason. This means we can no longer go on day trips or quick weekend getaways nearby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While all of this news was quite disheartening seeing as things in America are starting to normalize and most people I know have gotten at least one injection of the vaccine, some good news happened in the past ten days - Jack made it here safely ! After not only getting an Icelandic visa and and safely quarantining and spending 16 days in Iceland (not to mention getting to see an erupting volcano), he made it here on my birthday ! While he arrived just in time for confinement, he also arrived when the rest of us were celebrating our last few days of freedom and all being together. Definitely launched right into French life and meeting everyone all at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then it has largely been a nonstop hangout most every night and day because we as assistants do not have jobs and a couple of my close friends are leaving this week. It’s been a lot of emotions and a lot of things going on - happiness that Jack is here, sadness that people are leaving, anxiety at the uncertainty of the situation, frustration at the French government’s handling of the pandemic, and gratitude that I still have time to enjoy France and the weather is nice, and now I get to share it with Jack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One week of my unexpected three week vacation has passed, so for the next two weeks I will be working on catching up on the blog and getting myself back to regular posting, lots of cooking (especially slow recipes that require constant monitoring because I’ve got nothing but time), reading (just finished A Promised Land - while long, it was fascinating and I really enjoyed it), watching TV (finishing shows I’ve started months/years ago, Call my Agent, West Wing, some others), and getting some fresh air and enjoying spring in Provence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another emotion that has also been weighing on me is homesickness. On the one hand, I feel guilty being homesick when I get to live in France and enjoy a three week vacation. I know this is not only a crazy opportunity, but also an era in my life that is unique in I will never have this much free time again. On the other hand, seeing America reopen and people safely congregate and go to restaurants and see friends is tough knowing France is weeks, even months away from that. Knowing I will probably be going home before then is hard because I won’t fully get to experience what a lively, pandemic-free Avignon is like. On top of that, I’ve been here for almost seven months. While I went home for Christmas, it’s a long time to live abroad during a pandemic. I’ve been living under a curfew since January, and I honestly don’t know what it will be like to be out and about at night. But I remind myself that America isn’t going anywhere, and home is a feeling, not a place. So I will be enjoying this relaxing time before law school starts in the fall. And once I get home, a vaccine !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-24/Sunset Dos.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-24/Sunset Dos.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Twenty minutes pass and you can see how different it looks.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name>Mallory Shaner</name></author><category term="immersion" /><category term="France" /><category term="pandemic" /><category term="language" /><category term="travel" /><category term="French" /><category term="expat" /><category term="America" /><summary type="html">Can't not post these photos of the sunset and the street.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On COVID Frustration</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/On-COVID-Frustration/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On COVID Frustration" /><published>2021-03-28T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-03-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/On-COVID-Frustration</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/On-COVID-Frustration/">&lt;p&gt;Now that we have been living in this pandemic for over a year, I feel like I can write a blog post about it. There’s a lot that’s different about living in France vs. America during the pandemic, but today on this Monday as cases SOAR in France I would like to discuss frustration a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember arriving to France in October and being excited to enter a country where it seemed like they had a handle on the situation. This belief was mainly based in the fact that they had a competent leader unlike us at the time. But I also knew Europe had somewhat opened for travel for the summer, cases were decently low throughout the summer and early fall, and I felt confident going to a country that has free universal health care and what seemed to be a good policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I arrived, I was a little surprised at how little people social distanced, the amount of incorrectly donned masks I saw, and the fact that indoor dining continued unregulated (and outdoor for that matter). After three and a half weeks in France, this lackadaisical and unclear governing policy came to a peak and France shut down again. While the US never fully shut down in the same way that most of Europe and Asia did in the spring, things did kind of come to a screeching halt in March/April. It was hard to reconcile the fact that France was pausing again but the US wasn’t. But I felt okay about the strategy because cases were rising in the US and how long is a month really? Plus this lockdown promised way more freedom than the last.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After four weeks, the government changed restrictions slightly. Following a spike in cases from the holidays, France went into a nationwide curfew beginning at 6 PM until 6 AM. Stores were allowed to remain open and you no longer needed an attestation to leave your residence within the curfew hours, but restaurants and bars were still closed for dining / drinking in. The 6 PM curfew didn’t seem too bad at first, largely because January is cold and it gets dark at 4:30. There was hope of a change in February, to no avail. February things stayed exactly the same. The usual gossip of reentering confinement and potentially closing the schools for a few weeks abounded, but nothing came of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, not only did the US get a new president who recognized the severity of the pandemic, but vaccines began rolling out there rapidly. On the other hand, France’s vaccine supply was and still is not only limited due to sharing with other EU countries and exporting abroad, but fewer were approved. This is where I started to get really frustrated with the whole situation. Even though schools remain open in France, teachers are still not eligible to get vaccinated. Regardless of a pandemic, teachers are some of the most tireless and thankless workers in the world. On the other hand, I saw all of the people I know who teach in the US begin to get vaccinated. While I know the rollout has varied greatly by state, a large portion of my network is based in the tri-state area and they seem to have had a great vaccine program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While all of this is happening, I am still going to lunch with my teachers every day, who fall on two sides of the spectrum. There are the teachers I work with who are anti-vaccine and will think of any reason to not get it, and the teachers I work with who are disappointed with the government’s priorities and feel forgotten. When I shared that my grandparent’s had been vaccinated in February, they were all shocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it’s the end of March, and it feels like we’re stuck in a limbo here. Paris and a few other regions have just reentered confinement-lite, and while they moved the curfew in the rest of France back an hour to 7 PM to account for Daylight Savings, cases are exponentially rising and bars and restaurants show no signs of opening. Today, I realized that many places in L’Isle-sur-la-Sorgue and Avignon have literally not been open in just over 5 months. It’s insane. And it’s exhausting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s exhausting from a few different perspectives, and while I don’t want to complain because I do still get to live in France, the vastly different trajectories France and America are on with respect to the pandemic are taking a toll on me. While I readjusted my expectations of normalcy by December when we reconfined in October, I thought maybe by the spring with warmer weather we’d be rounding a corner. I was and remain wrong. It has been truly so weird to see people in America continue to travel, eat out, party in large groups, and generally seem to disregard the pandemic. On the other hand, my experience here has been one that is largely dictated by government rules and so even if I wanted to go out and have some sense of the old times, I wouldn’t be able to. Yet now that vaccines are more widespread, I feel myself growing increasingly jealous of the sense of normalcy returning to America - people can start traveling and eating out again safely. On the contrary, France is facing a third or fourth wave (depending on how you’re counting) and things do not seem to be slowing down. The tables have majorly turned. I not only find myself jealous, but also stuck. It feels like as America opens up, France is closing down more and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel badly complaining on the one hand because I know this is the opportunity of a lifetime, but I also not only feel a need to vent but to discuss the situation in France. COVID rules and regulations are hard to follow as is, but to follow amongst two countries is downright impossible. I just want to remember not only how I’m feeling, but also the specific frustrations and rules I’m dealing with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-24/Calanques Beauty.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-24/Calanques Beauty.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Hiking in the Calanques de Marseille, which were absolutely stunning. And the weather was perfect.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name>Mallory Shaner</name></author><category term="immersion" /><category term="France" /><category term="pandemic" /><category term="language" /><category term="travel" /><category term="French" /><category term="expat" /><category term="America" /><category term="Marseille" /><summary type="html">Now that we have been living in this pandemic for over a year, I feel like I can write a blog post about it. There’s a lot that’s different about living in France vs. America during the pandemic, but today on this Monday as cases SOAR in France I would like to discuss frustration a bit.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On Routine, Part II</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/On-Routine-Part-II/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Routine, Part II" /><published>2021-03-24T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-03-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/On-Routine-Part-II</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/On-Routine-Part-II/">&lt;p&gt;I wrote a blog post a couple of weeks back about routine and how important it is to have one, but I figured I should follow up with my actual routine here because it looks so different from my daily life working full time in Boston.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-24/Alpilles Again.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-24/Alpilles Again.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Hiking in the Alpilles, where Van Gogh painted many a masterpiece.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also know it’s been a while since I’ve posted so a lot of these pictures are from various different occasions. But all France!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-24/Alpine feels.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-24/Alpine feels.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Memories of Switzerland with the braids and mountains (and classic backpack of course).&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I only teach 3 days a week, it was a tough adjustment figuring out things to do on Wednesdays and Fridays (especially during confinement). But now I have a pretty good schedule. I figure there are definitely family members from home who are curious as well as one day I imagine I’ll want to look back on this and remember what life looked like here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-24/American food.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-24/American food.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;As I mention further down, the grocery store with only frozen food is amazing. Last week was America week and look at all of these options!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Mondays (because the French start the week with Monday and it makes way more sense) for my first 2ish months I wouldn’t wake up till 10:30 or 11 and eat a big brunch and then catch a 12:20 bus that got me to school right before class started. This was sort of stressful because if I need to make copies or run any ideas by the teachers I had 15 minutes (and they were usually finishing their own lesson planning so didn’t want to talk to me). Starting in January I started catching a 9:40 bus that gets in at 10:30. I usually wake up around 8:20, which is funny because that’s when I used to leave for work. I make a quick breakfast of toast and fruit and these days iced coffee and head off, reading and doing the crossword for my 50 minute ride. Once I get to L’Isle-sur-la-Sorgue, I usually head right to school and outline my lesson ideas before the teachers break for a two hour lunch break from 11:30-1:30. These two hours are the most French I speak on a weekly basis. I try to follow their conversations and discussions and occasionally chime in. They’ve usually brought a main dish, fruit for dessert, and yogurt. Sometimes they’ll add a salad. And they always have a baguette end to sop up the sauce. Then I teach for about 30-60 minutes in each class until 4:30, with one 30 minute break. It’s a sprint, not a marathon, and truly very exhausting to hop from class to class. My bus home isn’t till 5:30, so depending on the weather I either hang around school until I have to walk or walk around the town and stop at the grocery. Occasionally I nap on the bus home, but I usually read more. Once I get home, my roommate and I will usually work out for a little, cook dinner, eat around 8, then watch something or read or color the giant poster of France we bought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-24/Amigas and birthdays.JPG&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-24/Amigas and birthdays.JPG&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Celebrating birthdays on the Rhône is always a good choice.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tuesdays and Thursdays follow the same rough formula, with the exception that Thursdays there’s the local market and I always spend time walking around and buying stuff for cooking dinner and talking to the cheesemonger who has become my friend (Steph). He gives the largest free samples and I always end up too hungry for lunch. I also sometimes walk to this grocery store that only does frozen dishes but they are all AMAZING. French people also swear by it. It’s called Picard and everything I’ve tried has been delicious. I can’t think of an American equivalent because it has the frozen aspect of Trader Joe’s but is distinctly French and does not offer any non-frozen things (except for the odd chips or crackers). And it’s next to a delicious bakery that does baguettes made with wheat grown in L’Isle-sur-la-Sorgue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-24/Arles.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-24/Arles.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Arles was beautiful and it was cool to see the Rhône closer to the sea.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wednesdays and Fridays are a bit different since I don’t work. Now that it’s nicer and we don’t have confinement, I’ve been trying to go on day trips to nearby cities or day hikes. If I don’t do that, I will usually sleep in, sometimes have coffee with friends, go to Les Halles (indoor food hall in Avignon that has the best produce, meat, and cheese in the city/region) and get stuff for dinner. I like to go for a run too, and I’ve been trying to go to a new place for lunch each week. Then I usually nap or run errands / do laundry / go home and chill. Have a mid-week day off is amazing. I know have a three-day work week here, but I truly am a huge advocate these days for a four-day work week. It’s so nice to have a day where it’s not the weekend but you don’t have to worn and can run all your errands. I guess this is different in COVID times too because everything is remote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-24/Cake baking.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-24/Cake baking.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;We bake lots of cakes these days.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weekends of late have looked slightly different. With curfew, we try to take advantage of the daylight and do picnics or explore new towns and markets. Since people have to be home by 7, people sleep over a lot. It’s kind of like college but a lot tamer. Especially since everyone in Avignon lives within a 15 minute walk, it’s so easy to see people and meet up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-24/Exploring Arles.JPG&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-24/Exploring Arles.JPG&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Exploring Arles as a group of Anglophone assistants. We definitely stand out.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s definitely helped having a stable routine. Even in confinement, it looked fairly similar (with the difference being I had no roommate and therefore little motivation to work out / cook after school). But being very type A, I am definitely someone who thrives on routine and structure. Putting certain things in place every week has helped me not only fill my many idle hours but also feel a sense of place and purpose. Even if those things are just my weekly conversations with and purchases from the cheesemonger or Friday day trips, it’s a huge difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-24/LIsle and Yoda.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-24/LIsle and Yoda.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;My town is doing a Carnaval ambiance idea where they are placing mannequins of famous characters around town. Kind of cute.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s crazy to think how much my routine has changed since living and working in Boston and then COVID. And in a few months it’ll change again ! But change is part of life, as I have learned time and time again.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mallory Shaner</name></author><category term="immersion" /><category term="France" /><category term="pandemic" /><category term="language" /><category term="travel" /><category term="French" /><category term="expat" /><category term="America" /><category term="Paris" /><summary type="html">I wrote a blog post a couple of weeks back about routine and how important it is to have one, but I figured I should follow up with my actual routine here because it looks so different from my daily life working full time in Boston.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On Paris Always Being a Good Idea</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/On-Paris-Always-Being-a-Good-Idea/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Paris Always Being a Good Idea" /><published>2021-03-09T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-03-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/On-Paris-Always-Being-a-Good-Idea</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/On-Paris-Always-Being-a-Good-Idea/">&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-09/Conran shop.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-09/Conran shop.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;This store was so cool, and just one of the many places we discovered.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last two weeks we had vacation. It seems crazy to say this, but after seven weeks of teaching it felt very needed. It’s wild how quickly I’ve adjusted to getting lots of vacation (and how rude of an awakening returning to American ways of grinding away will be). Since France is still on a strict 6 pm curfew and restaurants and bars are still closed, our options for activities over the break felt somewhat limited. Ski resorts are not open, and a lot of the small towns are hard places to visit because much isn’t open right now with all the rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-09/Coutume.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-09/Coutume.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The blue espresso machine, modern furniture, and old ceilings made Coutume a very vibey coffee shop.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, we decided to go to Paris. Margaret’s mom’s friend has an apartment there, so we knew we had free lodging. She also needed someone to check on the apartment seeing as no one had been there in almost a year. We were there for almost a week, and it was truly amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-09/Fleuri.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-09/Fleuri.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;When we arrived, these flowers were about to bloom. On our last day, they did!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s funny because I have adjusted fairly well to living in the south in my fairly small city of Avignon. I’m used to the fact that things aren’t open Sunday afternoons and all day Monday. I’ve accepted that there’s one place to get iced coffee, and only three sushi restaurants. I’ve grown to love the slower paced nature, the focus on getting my ingredients at the local market and cooking myself, and the gorgeous, old, Provençal architecture. When we first arrived to Paris, it was actually kind of jarring. For starters, Paris was not its usual self. It was much less crowded than is typical. You didn’t see people having their morning beverages at the cafés, or lunching en terrasse spilling into the sidewalk with their cigarettes and glasses of wine. That being said, Paris is still the biggest city in France and one of the biggest in Europe. It was sort of weird seeing so many cars and people and the hustle and bustle that I was so used to in Boston (and growing up outside New York City).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-09/Invalides.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-09/Invalides.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;I had never walked by Les Invalides and it was quite peaceful.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first day, I felt myself missing Avignon. I missed knowing that I could wander around the city and never get too lost. On the other hand, we almost always had Google Maps up in Paris. I wasn’t used to crossing busy two way streets; because downtown Avignon is a very concentrated and old city center, most streets are one way and there’s very little automobile traffic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-09/La Tour.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-09/La Tour.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A photo that needs no caption.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the weeks leading up to this trip, and also much of the time I’ve spent in France this year, I was shocked I had yet to go to Paris. It is the city that made me fall in love with France, and is often the first stop when visiting the country. However, having now gone, I realize it was actually a really good thing I waited this long. Quite frankly, I think if I had visited Paris right when I got to France, I would have been really sad I didn’t choose to be placed there. I would have felt homesick, knowing the city I was placed in was far smaller and didn’t offer a lot of the conveniences I was used to. I think it was a huge thing for me to appreciate Avignon and also the year I’ve had living in Southern france because I realized that Paris is wonderful, but its very much its own thing. It’s a lot more international and cosmopolitan (re: similar to NYC), and also you hear a lot more English (as well as people automatically knowing you’re American since they’re used to it, and so they always respond to you in English). While I love Paris more than anywhere in the world, full stop, this trip made me realize there is so much more to France than the City of Lights. It made me feel very content with my decision to do this program where I’m doing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-09/Le bon marche.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-09/Le bon marche.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The famous Le Bon Marché, sadly closed.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that first day of adjusting to la grande ville and remembering to look both ways when I cross the street (hi Mom!!! I promise I did!!!) and getting used to being answered in my native tongue even when I asked in French, I remembered why Paris is ALWAYS a good idea. While restaurants, bars, and museums were closed, the stores were open. And if Paris is famous for anything in particular, I would say fashion ranks pretty highly as a contender. We had done some research beforehand on cool concept stores and unique boutiques. The soldes were still going on for a bit, so we did take advantage of that. We also found some outlet stores for the uber expensive brands we had seen on the street.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-09/Le celebre.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-09/Le celebre.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The classic sign.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though restaurants and bars were closed for dine-in, takeaway culture is alive and well in Paris. It’s not really as much of a thing culturally in France. French food itself doesn’t lend itself to being transportable (can you imagine eating a coq au vin out of tupperware ? Quelle horreur). But since Paris is massive and international and blends many cultures, there were tons of to go options. We focused a lot on food we couldn’t get in Avignon (Vietnamese, Thai, Mexican) and on cafés and bakeries. Having spent several years of my life in extremely cold climates, I am a year round iced coffee person. There’s one place in Avignon that does a good job, but in Paris we probably tried ten different cafés that each had their own version. They were all delicious. A fair amount of these cafés are also run by expats, so it was nice chatting with them and hearing about their COVID experience. Some highlights were Echo Deli, Café Kitsuné, Le Peloton Café (fun fact it is a French word that means a group of cyclists ! This place has nothing to do with those spin bikes), Dreamin’ Man, and Le Coutume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-09/Parc a Paris.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-09/Parc a Paris.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Walked around this gorgeous park on our last day.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other thing we focused on was bakeries, since it’s France and those are considered essential and were open. We found some amazing spots. We did our research here as well, finding that there’s a trend of more female-owned bakeries as well as a lot of spots that are offering renewed versions of classic items. Our typical move was to buy around 3 or 4 to share throughout the morning. That way we could sample a bunch, and we often had leftovers to act as dessert for lunch. Some standouts were Mamiche (the cinnamon roll and the vanilla cream puff were insane and literally brought us to tears), Du Pain et Des Idées (a friend told us to get the pistachio and chocolate snail and it was outstanding), and La Maison d’Isabelle for croissants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-09/Parc encore.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-09/Parc encore.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;There were so many adorable French toddlers frolicking around.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though it was not the Paris I am accustomed to, it felt very special to see it at such a unique time. It was still so lively and full of action, and I could feel the spirit of the city ready to wake up when this is all over. Biking along the grands boulevards, sipping cider along the Seine, and popping into a million adorable boutiques were wonderful ways to see the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-09/Parc trois.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-03-09/Parc trois.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;And, most importantly, a community garden.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name>Mallory Shaner</name></author><category term="immersion" /><category term="France" /><category term="pandemic" /><category term="language" /><category term="travel" /><category term="French" /><category term="expat" /><category term="America" /><category term="Paris" /><summary type="html">This store was so cool, and just one of the many places we discovered.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On Routine Part I</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/On-Routine/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Routine Part I" /><published>2021-02-20T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-02-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/On-Routine</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/On-Routine/">&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-20/My room.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-20/My room.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Arguably the most important part of establishing a routine is having a place to call home and be cozy. Behold - my room!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img right-inline&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-20/Amazing soup.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-20/Amazing soup.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Cooking delicious meals with Margaret is another important part of routine, both specifically to me but also I think to life in France in general.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It feels nice to say that after almost five months here, I can confidently say I have a routine. To be fair, moving three times would cause a disrupt in that routine easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-20/Fruits de mer.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-20/Fruits de mer.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;We went to a small gathering last weekend and they had two seafood platters, which felt kind of random. Accepting these random instances is just part of my routine.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img left-inline&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-20/Happy pup.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-20/Happy pup.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;This pup only had two legs but he looked happier than ever. Since it's less normal to pet dogs here, I just take creepy pictures from afar.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But since I feel less like writing and more like showing photos, I figured I’d make this a two-part post with the first part being photos of my day to day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-20/Juxtaposition.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-20/Juxtaposition.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;I guess since donuts aren't a huge thing here, cops have to eat baguettes? I really enjoyed the contradiction between the pastries and his gun. But again, part of my routine is getting bread very frequently (and trying new bakeries when I can).&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img right-inline&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-20/L'isle is my love.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-20/L'isle is my love.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;I love L'Isle-sur-la-Sorgue and seeing the beauty in it is also part of my daily routine.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am also on vacation for the next two weeks! It’s crazy because when it comes down to it, I’m in France for seven months but only teaching for 21 of those.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-20/Le parc.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-20/Le parc.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;I was going for a run on a gorgeous day and even though I had walked through this park before, I never noticed the stained glass window and church remnants. France is so gorgeous.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img left-inline&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-20/Leaning tower of Lices.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-20/Leaning tower of Lices.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Our apartment is in the building with the seafoam windows, and the building leans quite a bit. According to our landlord, this is because it's built on the original city walls.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I’m bummed to not be going home for this break, I am grateful that I get to go to Paris for a few days! I love Avignon but the thought of going to a big city (and not just any big city) is super exciting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-20/Colocs who match.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-20/Colocs who match.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Roommates (or colocs, in French slang) with matching scrunchies! That we bought from a female owned small business.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img right-inline&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-20/Regulars.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-20/Regulars.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Most days I go into this grocery store in L'Isle while I wait for the bus. This guy is usually outside with his dog playing the violin. The other day he was playing a hauntingly beautiful rendition of Hallelujah while it was raining and it was insane.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, it’s pretty wild that I’ve been in France for five months and this is the first time I’ll be going to Paris, which is the reason I fell in love with France in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-20/Seals.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-20/Seals.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;In middle school, we learned the word for seal in French was phoque, which sounds a lot like a curse word that us 12-year-olds were too scared to say. So we thought we were pretty cool saying it in French.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img left-inline&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-20/Sewing machines.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-20/Sewing machines.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;I went to get my haircut and all of the tables were made out of old sewing machines. I guess part of my routine is finding the beauty in normally ordinary things.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, here are some pictures from my day-to-day. I definitely think I have more of a tendency to take photos here because I try and notice everything. Hopefully it’s a habit I’ll continue with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-20/Valentines.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-20/Valentines.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Also routine - the kids I teach being adorable. They gave each other compliments in English for Valentine's day. And included me in the fun!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img right-inline&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-20/Walk to train.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-20/Walk to train.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;One of the parks near our apartment that I often eat lunch in on my days off. I like buying a meal from somewhere new (to support the restaurants!) and sitting in the park. Me and all the high schoolers. No, but it's actually quite nice.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name>Mallory Shaner</name></author><category term="immersion" /><category term="France" /><category term="pandemic" /><category term="language" /><category term="travel" /><category term="French" /><category term="expat" /><category term="America" /><summary type="html">Arguably the most important part of establishing a routine is having a place to call home and be cozy. Behold - my room!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On Missing America</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/On-Missing-America/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Missing America" /><published>2021-02-12T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-02-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/On-Missing-America</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/On-Missing-America/">&lt;p&gt;I was recently reading the blog post of another American assistant and she listed some things she missed about America. I’ve mentioned here and there but I don’t have a full list, so I thought that would be a good topic for this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Iced coffee - this was a major gripe abroad as well, especially in April, May, and June. I remember how easy it was to make cold brew in my French press in Geneva (and then, gasp, drink it on the bus much to the disgust of my fellow passengers). I have started doing the same here, even though it is February, because after having spent 4 years in upstate New York and 2 years in Boston anything above 45 degrees Fahrenheit is cold beverage weather. There’s one place near my new apartment that does great iced coffee, but that’s the only one I’ve found. I know it’s not really a thing in Europe as they drink espresso year round. But god. I miss Dunkin. I also miss iced lattes, which I won’t even bother to find because those are probably sacrilegious.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Small talk - I’ve talked before about how the teachers I work with aren’t really interested in small talk, or any sort of shoot-the-shit conversation. In America, I feel like it’s de rigueur, and I honestly don’t mind it. Except when it’s about the weather. That is just downright unnecessary. But here, it’s beyond just small talk. My teachers haven’t once asked me why I’m doing this program, or how I’m adjusting, or anything of that matter. I know it’s cultural and Americans are naturally very open and equally nosy people. But it’s a weird adjustment. I’m used to over sharing (thanks Mom!) and just generally enjoying chatting with people. I was talking to Robyn, the American bakery owner living in my town who invited me to Thanksgiving, about this. She mentioned how it’s such a thing in your 20s, especially in New York, to meet someone in line at the bathroom in a bar and share your life story. Whether or not you stay in touch isn’t a given. But that doesn’t happen here. That being said, she did mention how French people are better at staying in touch and the friendships they do have are quite meaningful. But I do miss small talk. And over sharing.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To go food and drink - probably could have combined this with iced coffee but alas. As many people know, France (and a lot of Europe) does not have a to go culture. It’s definitely gotten stronger, especially amidst the pandemic when take out is literally the only option for restaurants to make money here. But even so, it’s still way different. And I have yet to see take out of a classic French restaurant. Which makes sense - the cuisine is not nearly as transportable (can you imagine putting bœuf bourguignon in a Tupperware ? I shudder). But also just the idea of being able to eat while walking (this kind of builds on the thing of slowing down and not multitasking. Eating and walking is two things). All the lycéens in Avignon (HS students) always wait in line for their McDo, then eat it sitting in the park. I also learned that eating while driving is illegal here. Makes sense, but boy do I eat while driving a lot in America.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Driving / having a car - from an environmental perspective and public transportation being amazing here perspective, I arguably don’t miss this THAT much. But in COVID times this is definitely something I miss more because bus/train schedules here are still whack. I’m also in a region where it is best to explore by car because it’s hilltop villages, cliff side highways along the coast, and remote countryside areas. I remember abroad I didn’t miss this as much, but that’s because I was always on the go (and Geneva is so centrally located and has wonderful public transportation that it didn’t feel super necessary). Now that I am older and actually living here, it would be nice to have a car every once in a while. I also miss driving and listening to music, having the windows down, and feeling that notion of escape, which is so necessary in COVID. I remember in April, just driving to get takeout felt like jail breaking. Riding on a bus just doesn’t have the same sentiment. But I am also immensely grateful for the wonderful public transportation of Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Salads as meals - sweetgreen, if you see this, please ship to Europe. French people do eat a lot of veggies and do eat salads, but it’s very much as a starter or finisher to a meal. It’s usually light, just lettuce and dressing and maybe one raw veggie. And there are no takeout salad places (or even sandwich places that offer salads). I just miss having a filling salad with protein from sweetgreen that had perfect amounts of crunch and varying textures and was almost always dressed right. Margaret and I have made a few meal salads for dinner, but honestly nothing beats choosing each of your own ingredients, having it be dressed fully, and watching it made. I also always felt so light and healthy after eating a salad as a meal, which was great for lunchtime because I wouldn’t feel lethargic for the afternoon. Here, since lunch is two hours, I do tend to eat bigger meals. I don’t feel as lethargic though because my afternoons are filled with young French children shouting Hello at me without the H.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Athleisure being acceptable fashion to wear out and about - I think I mentioned this in my blog posts about fashion, but here wearing leggings as pants is NOT a thing. I only see people wearing leggings when working out, and even then it’s rare. I miss being able to run errands in leggings and a dry fit long sleeve without people staring at (or in some super annoying cases, catcalling) me. Sweats are definitely okay here in a trendy/millennial way, but that’s about it. I don’t see people wearing they’re skintight full on lululemon and athleta getups like I would in Boston. I also think maybe I was more surprised about this because there’s been such a shift towards athleisure in America due to the pandemic and working from home? But then I guess if those working from home ARE wearing athleisure, how would I know? I also miss not feeling self conscious in workout gear. Here, I get lots of stares when I’m on a run wearing leggings and a tank top. I see other people wearing workout clothes, but they’re definitely more conservative outfits. Athleisure and fitness clothes are just part of my daily life in America, and I miss being able to go outside in comfy, form fitting outfits without a second thought.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Breweries - this definitely isn’t just an abroad thing but also a pandemic thing. But I miss breweries. A lot. I miss being able to sit at a brewery for most of a Saturday, try a bunch of different beers and kick back flights, play board games, and bring in my own food. I miss being able to get growlers to bring home, sitting outside with Apollo, and having a place to go on the weekends. While this is partly a pandemic issue, breweries are also not as big of a thing in France. I mean, obviously. The alternative is sitting outside at cafes and drinking carafes of table wine for 12 euro. Which I do enjoy doing. But I miss interesting and flavorful craft beers. They are so refreshing, and the brewery experience (especially in Boston) is something really special in my opinion. I also can’t sit outside at cafes right now and drink carafes of table wine, so maybe that’s why I’m missing breweries especially. But I do remember missing it abroad to a degree as well, because there just wasn’t as much of a culture of small, independent, craft breweries then. I think it is expanding in Europe, but I haven’t seen any in Avignon.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Normal operating hours - this is something that Emily in Paris REALLY missed out on highlighting. There are very few stores here (and if they do exist they are usually large national chains and usually supermarkets) that are open 7 days a week, for the entire day without closing. For starters, restaurants here (especially amidst COVID) aren’t nonstop. They open usually from 11:30-2, then from 5-8 (on average). Other businesses that don’t serve food are often closed from 12-2. And then there’s the days of the week. In Avignon, for example, nearly everything is shut down from Sunday afternoon until Tuesday morning. Monday feels like a ghost town. The only things open are the grocery stores and maybe the post office. This can get very frustrating, especially when I first arrived, to figure out the system (and also to figure out where you CAN go if you didn’t plan correctly and need to shop on a Sunday or Monday). I miss knowing that things will be reliably open every day of the week. A few weeks ago my sister was headed to The Container Store on a Sunday, and I genuinely was shocked. I forget what it’s like to have the choice to go to businesses on Sundays. This might sound dramatic but it is kind of a hard adjustment. Additionally, the hours thing can get frustrating, especially since nothing is accurate on Google anymore due to COVID. On my days off, I often sleep in, eat a later breakfast and therefore want to eat a later lunch. This is usually not possible if I want to get something to take away since they are all closed. I’ve been here over four months now, and I still find myself confused by the schedules.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Petting other people’s dogs - this seems silly I’m sure. But when you don’t have a dog to go home to, petting other people’s dogs is a great way to get that quick dopamine hit. I remember in college if I ever saw a dog on campus I would run to it and ask to pet it. Even after Jack adopted Apollo in Boston and I did have a dog to go home to each night, I still found myself trying to pet any dog I saw on the street and often talk to them in a totally not weird way. In France seeing as I don’t have Apollo OR Gatsby I feel even more of a temptation to pet every dog I see. Classically, though, that is not very socially acceptable in France. To be fair, it wasn’t socially acceptable in America I think until recently. Anyway, I miss being able to just have it be totally normal to ask strangers to pet their dogs. I do it sometimes here, but people usually give me strange looks and I always feel kind of awkward. But there are some really cute dogs here.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is by no means an exhaustive list, and just because I miss these things does not mean I am not enjoying my time in France. But it was actually kind of fun to commemorate the things I miss (so I won’t take them for granted when I’m back home)!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mallory Shaner</name></author><category term="immersion" /><category term="France" /><category term="pandemic" /><category term="language" /><category term="travel" /><category term="French" /><category term="expat" /><category term="America" /><summary type="html">I was recently reading the blog post of another American assistant and she listed some things she missed about America. I’ve mentioned here and there but I don’t have a full list, so I thought that would be a good topic for this week.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On Finding Fun</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/On-Finding-Fun/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Finding Fun" /><published>2021-02-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-02-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/On-Finding-Fun</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/On-Finding-Fun/">&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-08/Amigas in Montpellier.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-08/Amigas in Montpellier.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Friends in a new city!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img right-inline&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-08/Another aqueduct.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-08/Another aqueduct.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Not uncommon to find an aqueduct in most places in this region of France due to the Romans.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost caught up on the backlog of blog posts when I was home for Christmas. On a Monday note, Mondays are always kind of tough, France or the US, pandemic or not. But this Monday was especially hard because I woke up to looking at all the Super Bowl snacks on Instagram stories and it didn’t only make me hungry but it made me kind of homesick for things like sliders, chicken wings (which, to be fair, I had last weekend), and buffalo chicken dip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-08/Another Arc de Triomphe.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-08/Another Arc de Triomphe.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Nothing like its namesake in Paris, but pretty (and yellowish).&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img left-inline&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-08/Antigone again.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-08/Antigone again.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Antigone is a neighborhood in Montpellier that was designed by a Catalonian architect.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today’s post is photo heavy because it was a busy and fun-filled weekend/week and reminded me that it is possible to have fun despite a 6 PM curfew, as long as you plan properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-08/Antigone.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-08/Antigone.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;It's supposed to be a planned area with long esplanades, green spaces, and fountains. It felt kind of utopian and futuristic.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img right-inline&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-08/Buttresses.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-08/Buttresses.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;I don't know why I enjoy this photo so much.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friday I went to Montpellier with a couple of assistants for the day. It was nice to be in a bit bigger of a city than Avignon that also felt way more lively than Nîmes. I also got some amazing poke that hit the spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-08/Conical cathedral.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-08/Conical cathedral.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The cones of this cathedral made me feel like I was in a video game.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img left-inline&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-08/Jardin again.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-08/Jardin again.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;We had to wait until 12 PM for this garden to open, but it was worth it.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Montpellier is one of the faster-growing cities in France and has a massive (25%) student population. It had lots of open spaces close to the centre ville and is within tram/biking distance to the beach (which I did not see).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-08/Jardin des plantes.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-08/Jardin des plantes.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Even though it was cloudy and overcast, there was an ethereal quality to the pants.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img right-inline&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-08/L'oratoire.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-08/L'oratoire.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Some more historical architecture in the center of town.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since museums are closed the main activity is to just walk around outside, but this botanical garden in the centre ville was open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-08/Old walls.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-08/Old walls.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Another part of the botanical garden.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img left-inline&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-08/Painted walls.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-08/Painted walls.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;I thought this was really cool - a mural of what this building might have once looked like.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, after a cloudy morning the sun came out in Montpellier. I definitely want to go back, hopefully when restaurants open!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-08/Parc.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-08/Parc.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Part of a massive open space right near centre ville&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img right-inline&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-08/Place de la comedie.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-08/Place de la comedie.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Kind of the main square in Montpellier - was very bustling even on a cloudy, COVID morning.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturday morning, Margaret and I were craving American breakfast sandwiches so I used a recipe I had made part of before, added bacon, used French ingredients, and bam. Amazing brunch, complete with mimosas with fresh squeezed OJ. We then had a very small housewarming gathering with some of the other assistants, which was a blast. Started early due to curfew, and then ended watching a movie, ordering in McDonalds, and playing guitar. Honestly, not bad for curfew and COVID.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-08/American breakfast.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-08/American breakfast.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Aforementioned amazing breakfast sandwich.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img left-inline&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-08/Party provisions.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-08/Party provisions.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;We looked pretty American leaving the supermarket with tons of chips. But also slightly French because we also bought cheeses and meats.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name>Mallory Shaner</name></author><category term="immersion" /><category term="France" /><category term="pandemic" /><category term="language" /><category term="travel" /><category term="French" /><summary type="html">Friends in a new city!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On Fashion, Part II</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/On-Fashion-Part-II/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Fashion, Part II" /><published>2021-02-04T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-02-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/On-Fashion-Part-II</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/On-Fashion-Part-II/">&lt;p&gt;As promised, a part II to last week’s fashion post. Slightly delayed but that is because I was moving apartments !!! Yes, for this keeping track at home this is my third move since getting to France. No, it does not get any easier but yes this apartment seems like it’s a keeper. I also have a roommate now and we do fun things together like eat baguettes while doing barre, cooking bomb meals made with fresh French ingredients, and puzzle while watching French TV. But since the delay in posts I also bought a FEW more soldes purchases, therefore ensuring I have a few more mirror pics to add to this week’s list (and a new mirror from which I am taking said pics).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-04/Cowboy look.jpg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-04/Cowboy look.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;This outfit was also mostly comprised of soldes purchases and a very old scarf from Madewell in literally 2010.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am still loving French fashion and since I last blogged I picked up a very fun and affordable teal corduroy jumpsuit that I would NEVER buy in America but which I love and I think suits me quite well. Margaret and I also went into this famous French ballet store (Repetto for those in the know) and bought ourselves barre outfits that are so freaking adorable. Also in classic French style the bags they came in are so cute and complete with ballet pink satin bows so I have rechristened it my lunch bag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-04/Dress and belt.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-04/Dress and belt.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;This dress and belt combo gives me all the southern France vibes.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now to the real interesting part - the next four principles. To be fair, I am sure there are SO many more. But this is what I’ve learned and what I’ve deemed to be the most important ones. Again, not an expert. Merely observing what I see and experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-04/French stripes.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-04/French stripes.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Sometimes the most classic looks (French navy stripes and camel colors) are the best.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Athleisure is not really a thing here. While I feel like athleisure clothes honestly make up half my wardrobe at home and I have been wearing leggings as pants since legit eighth grade, here that is not the case. Of course my teachers don’t, but out and about I never see French people wearing leggings and quick dry zip ups à la Lululemon. Even for working out, I feel judged when I wear leggings or shorts on a run. It’s funny to think about how in my day to day life in America, I would wear leggings as pants on the weekends to go grocery shopping or run out and get brunch. Here, I get stares if I walk into the grocery store in my workout outfit despite having just finished a run. Fitness is definitely becoming more of a thing here, and I see plenty of people (mostly men to be fair) when I’m on my runs in Avignon. But it’s definitely younger people that are bringing that here. I also was talking to two of the teachers with whom I work about their children’s experiences in American high schools and one of the things they pointed out was the fact that American high schoolers show up to class looking like they just rolled out of bed. I explained that that is for sure a thing and I can’t really justify it (although I would like to point out that I really tried to keep it ~stylish~ in high school and only allowed myself lazy sweats days once a week). Also I wondered how said French kids would feel showing up to a college final, where kids actually do wear their PJs. But alas, I digress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-04/Barre outfit.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-04/Barre outfit.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Aforementioned Repetto leggings complete with a wrap makes my barre outfit! Roommate and I have been doing it about 5 times a week and now we look the part.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shopping. For starters, as I’ve mentioned previously, this wonderful and bizarre phenomenon overtakes French stores for a month around January and a month around July known as the soldes. This is a time when nearly ALL the stores (both big box retail fast fashion and adorable boutiques and even market stands) put their stuff on MAJOR discount. For a month. And there’s usually a second markdown halfway through. I’m not entirely sure where it stems from but it is government regulated to an extent (hello pseudo-socialism), i.e. it can only be the days the government declares are the soldes period. The discounts are insane and it is not abnormal to find French people rushing out on their lunch breaks to peruse the offerings. You can find incredible deals on classic pieces. Even the luxury brands partake, which is super nice. There’s no real American equivalent because it doesn’t have the frenzy of Black Friday seeing how it lasts a month. Also, it’s usually a huge portion of the stock instead of just a small sale rack. And it’s not always just last season’s fashions. It’s amazing. Moreover, the shopping experience in general here is so different. There’s sort of this culture of taking your time, trying on tons of stuff (and the salespeople not giving you evil eyes if you buy nothing), and finding things you really like. French people have such great fashion maybe in part because the experience of acquiring clothes itself is so much better than in America. I walk into a store here and after exchanging the obligatory “Bonjour, comment ça va ?” the salesperson will ALWAYS ask me if they can help me find anything. I usually say no I’m just looking thanks. But if I am looking for something in particular they gladly offer suggestions out the wazoo, show me their favorites, and opine on what I’m trying on. Compare this to how impossible it often is to even find someone who works at a chain store in an American mall…. And then there’s the wrapping up. They often ask if you want it gift wrapped, and take the utmost care in packaging your purchases. If you say no, they still will gently and gracefully fold and place everything. It’s just so graceful and the opposite of rushed and really nice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-04/Jumpsuit.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-04/Jumpsuit.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;I bought this teal corduroy jumpsuit during the soldes and it gives me insane amounts of confidence.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Confidence is key. People think French people have this insane innate sense of style, which very well may be true. But I’m here to tell you that I think a huge part of that is confidence. I remember being so stressed about my program and my teachers liking me and everything and an American who had lived in France for a while reminded me that French people are too focused on their own lives to really care about strangers or anyone else. This holds true with respect to fashion I’ve found. The teachers I work with and the French people I’ve met and the French people I observe on the street have such a confident nonchalance about everything, but mostly fashion. They wear what they want and don’t care what others think. They walk proudly and unhurriedly, and also with that air of je ne sais quoi that I think just exudes confidence. Being surrounded by this has rubbed off on me. I take more risks with what I wear. I don’t care if something doesn’t look PERFECT because I know no one will notice. When it was cold earlier this year I would wear leggings under my dresses and three sweaters and not care how clunky it looked because they were all doing the same thing. It’s so refreshing to be around rather than Americans who are constantly adjusting their outfits and commenting on how they look.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-04/New jeans.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-04/New jeans.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;It's funny because all of the high schoolers here wear this style of jeans but it's so long on them and they look like they're always about to trip.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fast fashion vs. boutiques. This is a huge one for me. It could be due in part to where I am placed though I remember Angers having a ton of individually owned boutiques/businesses and I know in Paris the little boutiques in the Marais and Montmartre are the GOAT. So I think this is true of a lot of France, that boutiques are still very much a thing here, which is not really the case in big cities in America. I feel like you can hunt for them and occasionally find some good ones, but on the whole it is mainly chain stores, many of which are selling fast fashion (which as we know is terrible for the industry and the environment and the small business economy). I love that in Avignon I can walk around all the small boutiques and find unique dresses and shirts. In L’Isle sur la Sorgue the boutiques veer towards the home decor side due to the antique market, but I love it nonetheless. It is such a change from walking into a giant American shopping mall and seeing the same things you saw from the marketing email you got from that company for whom you once signed up for rewards. It’s refreshing and is something I am absolutely going to miss. I also think it’s a huge reason why French people have good fashion - they don’t all always look the same. Yes, H and M are Zara are big here. But the difference is is that they seem to coexist healthily (to the untrained eye) alongside the standalone boutiques. I wish we had more of that in America. Growing up, I remember the individual small businesses on the main streets of Rye and Larchmont. Those have been replaced by Starbucks and other chain restaurants, because now so many people either shop at the mall or online. Shopping online is so not a huge thing here. Which is amazing because it also means when I see the clothes in store, it’s the first time seeing them. Compared to shopping at home, I always look at the clothes online and either order them there or go into the store and buy what I saw online. But regardless, I’m buying clothes based on what they look like on a model, not what they look like on me. It makes a massive difference in confidence and style and I’m here for it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-04/Shorts and tights.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-04/Shorts and tights.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Shorts over tights are a look here and probably coming back to the US soon.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like many of these tenets are very similar. I also feel like perhaps what I’m writing could make zero sense and be completely false. Anyway, hope you enjoyed reading my thoughts ! Because that is all this blog is really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-04/The hat returns.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-02-04/The hat returns.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The hat always comes back.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name>Mallory Shaner</name></author><category term="immersion" /><category term="France" /><category term="pandemic" /><category term="language" /><category term="travel" /><category term="French" /><summary type="html">As promised, a part II to last week’s fashion post. Slightly delayed but that is because I was moving apartments !!! Yes, for this keeping track at home this is my third move since getting to France. No, it does not get any easier but yes this apartment seems like it’s a keeper. I also have a roommate now and we do fun things together like eat baguettes while doing barre, cooking bomb meals made with fresh French ingredients, and puzzle while watching French TV. But since the delay in posts I also bought a FEW more soldes purchases, therefore ensuring I have a few more mirror pics to add to this week’s list (and a new mirror from which I am taking said pics).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On Fashion, Part I</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/On-Fashion-Part-I/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Fashion, Part I" /><published>2021-01-28T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-01-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/On-Fashion-Part-I</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/On-Fashion-Part-I/">&lt;p&gt;I could honestly wax poetic about France and fashion. Though not like Emily in Paris. Amongst the ten thousand unrealistic things in that series, I would say her wardrobe is the one that irks me the most. Not only does it seem impossible to dress like that on a young marketing professional’s salary, no one dresses like that, especially in Paris. Her outfits are intentionally outlandish to evoke the whole living abroad vibe, but as someone who is American and living in France I would like to dispel a lot of those stereotypes. I also probably should stop holding on so tight to the inaccuracies in the series because it is just TV after all (and Bridgerton wasn’t realistic either but it did provide the escape we needed)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-01-28/Boots and buttons.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-01-28/Boots and buttons.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Classic color combo for me here: navy, off white, and camel brown.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt; This is going to be a two part blog post because obviously fashion and France are synonymous and to give it anything less than full attention would be wrong. Also, this post is of course filled with mirror selfies of my outfits here. Because I love them infinitely more than anything I wear in America.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-01-28/Casual.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-01-28/Casual.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;I also feel chic-er in the most basic of outfits, just by virtue of being in France.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Important disclaimer: while I talk like a seasoned expert these are purely my experiences in a small region of France and I am by no means a connoisseur and am simply offering my observations (albeit with somewhat of a tone of authority).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-01-28/Overalls and sweater.jpg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-01-28/Overalls and sweater.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;I didn't think overalls would be appropriate to wear to work. But then I saw a teacher doing it, so I copied her.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few things I’ve learned about fashion since moving here (although, to be fair, a couple of these things I learned in my other spells in France/abroad).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-01-28/Return of the leather jacket.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-01-28/Return of the leather jacket.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;If you remember my abroad days, this leather jacket featured heavily in most photos. Of course it is back.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simple is best. It’s no secret that a Parisian uniform is a black turtleneck and jeans, riffed on many different ways (cute booties, Hermès scarf, beige trench). But this holds true not just for Paris but for the rest of France. My teachers and the people I’ve encountered around Provence have some of the simplest, most classic style I’ve ever seen. Most people seem to have a couple of staples they wear on repeat (one teacher has a pair of high-healed Tim’s she wears with EVERY outfit, another has a Saint James sweater that goes with a lot, and in classically French fashion, another teacher wears the same scarf week after week). Major caveat being that I see these teachers once a week so it’s more likely than not that their outfits change every week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-01-28/Stripes and velvet.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-01-28/Stripes and velvet.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Playing with textures and my favorite sweater that feels very French.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Versatility is important. I have tried to incorporate this rule into my shopping from a young age. I’m not entirely sure where I learned it but I do know there must be some version in France as well based on my observations: before you buy anything, think of three potential and varied outfits you can wear with it. Super important to make sure you’re not just buying something that will only work with one pair of pants. I find a lot of French people wearing giant scarves that they can bundle up while outside but can wear more as ponchos/wraps indoors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-01-28/Trench again.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-01-28/Trench again.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;I forgot how much I loved this coat from last winter. Happily but also sadly it's been quite warm of late so I haven't been rocking it as much.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Accessorize. I’ve noticed while shopping it’s not totally uncommon to have the person working at the store tell you to try the dress with a belt or add a pair of heels to get the full look. I think this is a majorly important aspect of fashion here that complements both previous points. If you have a simple wardrobe, all you need to stand out amongst others is a couple of good accessories. Belts are big here, with jeans or cinching in a dress. Obviously the ever classic scarf is omnipresent and it’s important to have ones that are not only versatile color wise but season wise too. Jewelry is important too: everyone wears rings (though not everyone wears engagement/wedding rings, go figure). And shoes are just as much a part of an outfit as any other piece. I find my outfits definitely tend to be more simple here, but I always add a scarf, belt, or cool jewelry to give it a pop of color or something to keep it from being too basic. It seems like it’s written on every fashion blog ever to accessorize well, but it is definitely something that works in practice here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-01-28/Scarf and LBD.jpg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-01-28/Scarf and LBD.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Case in point re previous principle.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The importance of classics: capsule wardrobes are EVERYWHERE these days but I have to say that France does them best. For starters, it doesn’t seem to be some sort of Instagram trend here. It’s more a principle of the classics being timeless. The mentality of fewer, better is one that I’ve tried to inscribe in my brain from a sustainability purpose, but it’s definitely a practice in France. I see my teachers wearing a lot of the same outfits, but it’s classic styles that always work - a giant scarf that can be adapted to any outfit, a great pair of black boots, a simple pair of jeans, a navy and white striped sweater. I think due to its close association with fashion historically, people think French people are these avant-garde, super adventurous dressers. And don’t get me wrong, I see that on the street a fair amount here (though not nearly as ubiquitous as New York). But for the most part, I see people wearing the eternal staples. French fashion is on the whole, less complicated and simpler than fashion in America.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;post-img block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-01-28/Trench and hat.jpeg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/2021-01-28/Trench and hat.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;This coat + this hat feels very classic and yet unique at the same time. And these items do go with everything.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name>Mallory Shaner</name></author><category term="immersion" /><category term="France" /><category term="pandemic" /><category term="language" /><category term="travel" /><category term="French" /><summary type="html">I could honestly wax poetic about France and fashion. Though not like Emily in Paris. Amongst the ten thousand unrealistic things in that series, I would say her wardrobe is the one that irks me the most. Not only does it seem impossible to dress like that on a young marketing professional’s salary, no one dresses like that, especially in Paris. Her outfits are intentionally outlandish to evoke the whole living abroad vibe, but as someone who is American and living in France I would like to dispel a lot of those stereotypes. I also probably should stop holding on so tight to the inaccuracies in the series because it is just TV after all (and Bridgerton wasn’t realistic either but it did provide the escape we needed)!</summary></entry></feed>