<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-10-09T09:44:34-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Travels with Mally</title><subtitle>Tales of an American who moved to the south of France during the coronavirus pandemic.
</subtitle><author><name>Mallory Shaner</name></author><entry><title type="html">On My First Week</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/On-My-First-Week/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On My First Week" /><published>2020-10-09T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-10-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/On-My-First-Week</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/On-My-First-Week/">&lt;p&gt;Salut tout le monde! It has been a week since I’ve arrived in France and here we are. A week filled with tears, happiness, successes, failures, and everything in between. &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/airbnbview.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;View from my AirBnB&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has not been an easy week, but I knew it wouldn’t be (I just don’t think I realized that as I spent my last month at home saying goodbye to friends, finishing my job, packing, and enjoying living in the comfort of my parents’ home). It has been filled with lots of tears and moments of questioning why I did this in general, and also why I did this in the middle of a pandemic. The hardest part for me is not knowing if my loved ones will be able to visit me while I am here, and I need to keep reminding myself to take it one day at a time. Everything is temporary, including this situation, therefore I should enjoy it as much as possible. When else in my life will I be living alone in the south of France and teaching a mere 12 hours a week (which I don’t have to start doing until November anyway….)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/morelsls.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;L'Isle-sur-la-Sorgue is famous for its water wheels and waterways&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had planned on spending my first week in the town where I am assigned to teach, L’Isle-sur-la-Sorgue. It is a town famous for its vast Sunday market and antique fairs. It has many adorable shops, cute bistros, and little canals and pedestrian bridges over its waterways. My AirBnB is a little apartment that has everything I need to spend a couple of days, except other people. I felt very isolated the first few days because I knew no one in the town. Coming off of spending the past six months living in a condo with my entire family and seeing tons of people before I left, this was challenging. I realized I am not good at quiet. The mornings have been the hardest part of the day for me, when no one back home is awake. I listen to lots of podcasts because hearing English and the American accents calms me, and staying connected to the news makes me feel tied to home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/foodmarche.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Food from the famous Sunday market!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I move to a longer term AirBnB in the bigger city of Avignon this afternoon, and I am very excited for that. There are lots of other assistants de langue in Avignon, from the US and elsewhere (so far I have met assistants from the UK, Italy, Brazil, India, and Germany - with more to come I am sure). Avignon is a beautiful town filled with old city walls, ancient architecture, and winding streets full of little cafes to have un café ou un verre de vin. I am very excited to explore its secret alleyways and discover its hole-in-the-wall restaurants. My commute to my schools is about 25 minutes on the train, which runs somewhat randomly. I visited my schools and start my observation period Monday. They also are giving me Wednesdays and Fridays off - can’t complain about that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/avignonchurch.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;A beautiful park and church right in downtown Avignon.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am in a truly beautiful region of France that I am excited to explore more of (as well as the rest of the country). The people here have been much nicer than many of the Parisians I’ve encountered in my life. The food is of course delicious, and the wine is very cheap, though I’ve also been drinking a fair amount of beer. While I am very homesick still and crave bits of America, I know with time I will start listening to French podcasts, getting to know French music, making French friends, and cooking French food. I am appreciative of everything in my life that has led me here, and I am trying my best to take full advantage of it. I find myself at times feeling regretful of my first few months of college, when I was miserably homesick and instead of joining clubs or making friends I sat in my room crying or calling my parents. I am older now, and I am a stronger person. I can do anything I set my mind to, whether that is getting out of bed in the morning, making it through a day without crying, or spending 7ish months in France.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/friendsavignon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Drinking wine on the border of the Rhône river with new friends.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some observations from my first week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;grapes here are not seedless. but that hasn’t stopped me from eating the seeds.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;french people are definitely trendy but it’s not because they wear these crazy fashionable things, it’s because they were simple clothes with confidence. that’s the difference.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the attitude towards coronavirus is not like it was in the US.  people wear masks, but no one social distances really. people see this as just a facet of life now, but are continuing as normal otherwise.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;french bureaucracy is no fun and rather confusing/overwhelming.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;i am no longer ashamed to be american which is ironic because now is the time to be most ashamed. when i was in geneva i did everything i could to appear not american. here i’m realizing, ok at this point i know that it’s fairly easy to pick us out of a lineup just because.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;specific to covid: surgical masks are much more popular than personal cloth masks here. but i love my cloth masks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;french people don’t multitask. they don’t walk and talk on the phone, or walk and eat, or walk and drink coffee. they much prefer to do one thing at a time. i have gotten a lot of looks for walking around and being on the phone or texting. but i get those looks in the US sometimes too.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the produce here is fresher, but that means it goes bad more easily. and they don’t refrigerate eggs! i remember this from geneva but i kinda forgot about it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/moreavignon.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;The view of Avignon from the island in the middle of the river - you can see the Palais des Papes from here&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mallory Shaner</name></author><category term="Adjustment" /><category term="Moving" /><category term="Avignon" /><category term="Transition" /><summary type="html">Salut tout le monde! It has been a week since I’ve arrived in France and here we are. A week filled with tears, happiness, successes, failures, and everything in between.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On Leaving</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/On-Leaving/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Leaving" /><published>2020-10-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-10-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/On-Leaving</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/On-Leaving/">&lt;p&gt;As probably everyone who is reading this can guess, I am leaving for France in approximately 6 hours. I am moving there for about 8 or 9 months to teach English to French elementary schoolers in a small town called L’Isle-sur-la-Sorgue. It is known as the Venice of Provence with its waterwheels and rivers, and famous for its antique fairs and weekly market. To say I am excited would be an understatement, but to say that I am apprehensive is also true. I have spent the past year and a half dreaming about this day and this moment, and it looks kind of like I thought it would. It is the days, weeks, and months before that were nothing that I imagined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been fairly ambivalent about leaving for the last month. Honestly, my friends and family seem arguably more excited than I am. And I think the reason is a combination of two feelings. One is that since March, I had prepared myself for this program not to happen. I had come up with contingency plans, mentally told myself I would stay in my job for another year, and committed to delaying this almost-lifelong dream for another time. When I was accepted in late June (which was over two months later than planned), I didn’t let myself experience full excitement yet. There were a few other hurdles to get over. I had little bits of joy as I got closer and closer to my goal: happiness when I got in, cautious optimism when I found out it would be happening as a whole but was uncertain for Americans, relief when I found out Americans would be able to get visas, and finally, eagerness as I figured out how to get a COVID test in 72 hours. I would always correct people who asked when I was moving to France with a “hopefully, in late September.” Today is finally the day where I feel confident to say it’s happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other reason, which is ironically somewhat the opposite of the first, is that I think deep down, some part of me always knew this was going to happen. It was a matter of when. This was an inevitability in my life, kind of like going to college or moving out of my parents’ house (and I would like to take a moment to acknowledge the privilege that comes with all of these things). Now that this moment is here, it’s kind of like, ‘yeah, this is happening, but wasn’t it always going to?’ Once I hit the mark of knowing I could get in the country, I had not only spent so much energy silently wishing the program would happen, I also was ready. Maybe I’m also a little superstitious, and didn’t want to jinx myself. I spent a lot of time these past few months knocking on wood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I said previously, the months leading up to my departure were not how I planned them. I did not get to say goodbye to the city I lived in and loved for the past 2ish years, and I miss Boston dearly. I did not get to say goodbye to my coworkers or friends in the ways I had planned. I did not get to spend time enjoying New England summers with Jack in the ways I had imagined. But that’s okay. I did get six and a half bonus months of time with my parents, my sister, and my dog. I got to live in a beautiful place on the water and not have to grocery shop for myself. I got to see Jack every few weeks, which made each time that much more special. And while I didn’t have one big goodbye party where I could say farewell to those close to me, I relished spending time in smaller groups of friends and reconnecting with old ones. All this to say that I really should adhere to the adage that God laughs when you try to make plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post really has helped me put into words my bittersweet feelings about leaving at a time in my life when I feel fairly content. But perhaps that is the best time for a change, no?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mallory Shaner</name></author><category term="France" /><category term="Travel" /><category term="Departure" /><category term="Moving" /><summary type="html">As probably everyone who is reading this can guess, I am leaving for France in approximately 6 hours. I am moving there for about 8 or 9 months to teach English to French elementary schoolers in a small town called L’Isle-sur-la-Sorgue. It is known as the Venice of Provence with its waterwheels and rivers, and famous for its antique fairs and weekly market. To say I am excited would be an understatement, but to say that I am apprehensive is also true. I have spent the past year and a half dreaming about this day and this moment, and it looks kind of like I thought it would. It is the days, weeks, and months before that were nothing that I imagined.</summary></entry></feed>